greatist.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy Policy | Greatist

Effective Date of Current Policy: April 9, 2019

Greatist is committed to being your most trusted ally in your pursuit of health and well-being. Whether you're here to learn more about a health condition, tap into one of our communities, or get tips for a healthier lifestyle, you're in the right place. Behind all our content is a compassionate team of professionals who genuinely care about the health of you and your loved ones.

By visiting and interacting with our Website, We'll ask you to share certain information with Us, as detailed below.  We may use some of the information you share with Us to serve you relevant advertising. 

We want to ensure you understand the information We collect, how We use it, how We share it, and how you can control your information.  Please read our Privacy Policy in its entirety, and don't hesitate to reach out to us at [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com) if you have any questions about our privacy practices.

### Table of Contents

  * Introduction
  * What Personal Information do we collect and how we use it?
    * Types of Personal Information we collect
    * How do we use the information we collect?
    * Cookies, Pixel Tags/Web Beacons, Analytics Information, and Interest-Based Advertising
    * Third-Party Websites and Social Media Platforms
    * Third-Party Payment Processing
  * With whom do we share that information?
  * Do we collect information from children?
  * What security measures do we take with respect to your information?
  * Opt-out rights (rights to object to processing)
  * Website Location, US Transfer & Processing
  * Rights of Access, Rectification, Erasure, and Restriction
  * Data Retention
  * International Users
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Contact Us
  * Revision History

### 1\. Introduction

At Greatist, we respect your privacy and have established this Privacy Policy to describe our policies and practices with respect to the information that we collect from users of our Services. This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the Greatist Terms of Use (the “ **Terms** ”). Please review this Privacy Policy before you use our Services. By using our Services, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. So, please make sure that you have read and understand our Terms. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Services. All other capitalized terms not defined herein will have the meanings set forth in the Terms.

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information that is Processed by Greatist in the course of our business, including on the Website (together with any and all future online and offline offerings operated by or on behalf of Greatist, the “ **Services** ”). All individuals whose responsibilities include the Processing of Personal Information on behalf of Greatist are expected to protect that data by adherence to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is intended to meet requirements globally, including those in North America, Europe, APAC, and other jurisdictions.

This Policy applies to all Greatist’s operating divisions, subsidiaries, affiliates, and branches, and any additional subsidiary, affiliate, or branch of Greatist that we may subsequently form.

BY INSTALLING, USING, REGISTERING TO OR OTHERWISE ACCESSING ANY SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND GIVE AN EXPLICIT AND INFORMED CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT VISIT, INSTALL, USE, REGISTER TO OR OTHERWISE ACCESS ANY SERVICES.

 **Personal Information:** Any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“Individual”).

 **Sensitive Data** or **Sensitive Personal Information** : A subset of Personal Information which, due to its nature, has been classified by law or by policy as deserving additional privacy and security protections. Sensitive Personal Information includes Personal Information regarding EU residents that is classified as a “Special Category of Personal Data” under EU law, which consists of the following data elements: (1) race or ethnic origin; (2) political opinions; (3) religious or philosophical beliefs; (4) trade union membership; (5) genetic data; (6) biometric data where Processed to uniquely identify a person; (6) health information; (7) sexual orientation or information about the Individual’s sex life; or (8) information relating to the commission of a criminal offense.

### 2\. What Personal Information do we collect and how we use it?

The types of Personal Information we may collect (directly from you or from Third-Party sources) and our privacy practices depend on the nature of the relationship you have with Greatist and the requirements of applicable law. Some of the ways that Greatist may collect Personal Information include:

You may provide Personal Information directly to Greatist through interacting with the Services, participating in surveys, registering to receive our Newsletters, during events such as sweepstakes, and requesting Services, or information.

As you navigate the Services, certain passive information may also be collected about your visit, including through cookies and similar technologies as described below.

We endeavor to collect only that information which is relevant for the purposes of Processing. Below are the ways we collect Personal Information and how we use it.

#### 1\. Types of Personal Information we collect

Greatist collects Personal Information regarding its current, prospective, and former clients, customers, users, visitors and guests (collectively “ **Individuals** ”):

  *  **Information You Provide Directly to Us.** When you use the Services or engage in certain activities, such as registering to receive our Newsletters, participating in surveys, sweepstakes or contests, or otherwise interacting or requesting information on the Services, we may ask you to provide some or all of the following types of information:
    *  **Communication with Us.** We may collect Personal Information from you, such as your name, postal address, email address and phone number when you chose to request information about our Services, register for our Newsletter, or otherwise communicate with Us.
    *  **Surveys.** From time to time, we may contact you to participate in online surveys. If you do decide to participate, you may be asked to provide certain information which may include Personal Information. All information collected from your participation in our surveys is provided by you voluntarily. We may use such information to improve our Services and in any manner consistent with the policies provided herein.
    *  **Posting on the Website.** Greatist may offer publicly accessible pages or blogs on the Website. You should be aware that, when you disclose information about yourself in on Greatist’s publicly accessible pages or blogs, the Website will collect the information you provide in such submissions, including any Personal Information. If you choose to submit content to any public area of the Website, such content will be considered “public” and will not be subject to the privacy protections set forth herein.
    *  **Registration for Sweepstakes or Contests.** Occasionally, Greatist may run sweepstakes and contests.  We ask those who enter in the sweepstakes or contests to provide contact information (e.g., an e-mail address).  If you participate in a sweepstakes or contest, your contact information may be used to reach you about the sweepstakes or contest, and for other promotional, marketing and business purposes.  In compliance with the laws of your jurisdiction, as a participant you will have the opportunity to opt out of any communications that are not related to awarding prizes.
    *  **Automatic Data Collection.** We may collect certain information automatically through our Services or other methods of web analysis, such as your Internet protocol (IP) address, cookie identifiers, mobile carrier, mobile advertising identifiers, MAC address, IMEI, Advertiser ID, and other device identifiers that are automatically assigned to your computer or device when you access the Internet, browser type and language, geo-location information, hardware type, operating system, Internet service provider, pages that you visit before and after using the Services, the date and time of your visit, the amount of time you spend on each page, information about the links you click and pages you view within the Services, and other actions taken through use of the Services such as preferences.
  *  **Information from Other Sources.** We may receive information about you from other sources, including through third-party services and organizations to supplement information provided by you. For example, if you access our Services through a Third-Party application, such as an App Store or social network site (“ **SNS** ”), we may collect information about you from that third-party application that you have made public via your privacy settings. Information we collect through App Stores or SNS accounts may include your name, your SNS user identification number, your SNS user name, location, sex, birth date, email, profile picture, and your contacts on the SNS. This supplemental information allows us to verify information that you have provided to Greatist and to enhance our ability to provide you with information about our business and Services.

#### 2\. How do we use the information we collect?

We acquire, hold, use, and Process Personal Information about Individuals for a variety of business purposes, including:

  *  **To Provide Services or Information Requested.** Greatist may use information about you to fulfill requests for Services or information, including information about potential or future Services, including to:
    * conduct and process transactions with you;
    * communicate with you, such as to respond to your inquiries, send you Newsletters, notify you if you are a winner of a contest or sweepstakes, or notify you of any changes to the Terms that govern our Services or any changes to this Privacy Policy.
  *  **Administrative Purposes.** Greatist may use Personal Information about you for its administrative purposes, including to:
    * measure interest in our Services;
    * improve our Services and develop new services;
    * enforce the Terms that govern our Services or this Privacy Policy;
    * protect our Services, systems, information, employees, business partners, service providers, users, customers or others;
    * verify Individual identity;
    * prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; and
    * process payment for Services purchased.
  *  **Marketing Greatist Services.** Greatist may use Personal Information to provide you with materials about offers, products, and Services that may be of interest, including new content or Services. Greatist may provide you with these materials by email, as permitted by applicable law. Such uses include:
    * To tailor content, advertisements, and offers;
    * To notify you about offers, products, and services that may be of interest to you;
    * To provide Services to you and our sponsors;
    * For other purposes disclosed at the time that Individuals provide Personal Information; or
    * Otherwise with your consent.

You may contact Us at any time to opt out of the use of your Personal Information for marketing purposes, as further described in Section 6 below.

  *  **Research and Development.** Greatist may use Personal Information to create non-identifiable information that we may use alone or in the aggregate with information obtained from other sources, in order to help Us to optimally deliver our existing products and Services or develop new products and Services. From time to time, Greatist may perform research (online and offline) via surveys. We may engage Third-Party service providers to conduct such surveys on our behalf. All survey responses are voluntary, and the information collected will be used for research and reporting purposes to help Us better serve Individuals by learning more about their needs and the quality of the products and services we provide. The survey responses may be utilized to determine the effectiveness of our Services, various types of communications, advertising campaigns, and/or promotional activities. If an Individual participates in a survey, the information given will be used along with that of other study participants. We may share anonymous Individual and aggregate data for research and analysis purposes.
  *  **Email.** Individuals who provide Us with Personal Information, or whose Personal Information we obtain from Third Parties, may receive periodic emails and Newsletters from Us with information on Greatist’s or our business partners’ products and services or upcoming special offers/events we believe may be of interest. We offer the option to decline these communications at no cost to the Individual by following the instructions in Section 6 below.
  *  **Anonymous and Aggregated Information Use.** Greatist may use Personal Information and other information about you to create anonymized and aggregated information, such as de-identified demographic information, de-identified location information, information about the computer or device from which you access Greatist’s Services, or other analyses we create. Anonymized and aggregated information is used for a variety of functions, including the measurement of visitors’ interest in and use of various portions or features of the Services. Anonymized or aggregated information is not Personal Information, and Greatist may use such information in a number of ways, including research, internal analysis, analytics, and any other legally permissible purposes. We may share this information within Greatist and with Third Parties for our or their purposes in an anonymized or aggregated form that is designed to prevent anyone from identifying you.
  *  **Sharing Content with Friends or Colleagues.** Greatist’s Services may offer various tools and functionalities. For example, Greatist allows you to provide information about your friends through our referral services, such as “Tell a Friend.” Our referral services may allow you to forward or share certain content with a friend or colleague, such as an email inviting your friend to use our Services. Email addresses that you may provide for a friend or colleague will be used to send your friend or colleague the content or link you request, but will not be collected or otherwise used by Greatist or any other Third Parties for any other purpose.
  *  **Other Uses.** Greatist may use Personal Information for which we have a legitimate interest, such as direct marketing, individual or market research, anti-fraud protection, or any other purpose disclosed to you at the time you provide Personal Information or with your consent.

#### 3\. Cookies, Pixel Tags/Web Beacons, Analytics Information, and Interest-Based Advertising

We, as well as Third Parties that provide content, advertising, or other functionality on our Services, may use cookies, pixel tags, local storage, and other technologies (“ **Technologies** ”) to automatically collect information through the Services. We use Technologies that are essentially small data files placed on your computer, tablet, mobile phone, or other devices (referred to collectively as a "device") that allow Us to record certain pieces of information whenever you visit or interact with our Services, and to recognize you across devices:

  *  **Cookies:** We may utilize “cookies” to maintain a record of your visits and to improve the content and Services. Cookies are text files placed in your computer’s browser to store your preferences. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Websites. Most browsers allow you to block and delete cookies. However, if you do that, the Website may not work properly. To learn more about how you can control the use of cookies, visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.
  *  **Pixel Tags/Web beacons:** A pixel tag (also known as a web beacon) is a piece of code embedded on the Website that collects information about users’ engagement on that web page. The use of a pixel allows Us to record, for example, that a user has visited a particular web page or clicked on a particular advertisement.
  *  **Social Media Widgets:** Our Website includes social media features and widgets such as the share this button or other interactive mini-programs. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. These social media features are either hosted by a Third Party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
  *  **Analytics.** We may use Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to collect information regarding visitor behavior and visitor demographics on some of our Services, and to develop website content. This analytics data is not tied to any Personal Information. For more information about Google Analytics, please visit [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). You can opt out of Google’s collection and Processing of data generated by your use of the Services by going to <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Our uses of such Technologies fall into the following general categories:

  *  **Strictly Necessary Cookies.** We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies that are necessary to the operation of our Services. This includes technologies that allow you access to our Services; that are required to identify irregular site behavior, prevent fraudulent activity and improve security; or that allow you to make use of our functions such as saved search, or similar functions;
  *  **Performance Cookies.** We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies to assess the performance of our Services, including as part of our analytic practices to help us understand how our visitors use our Services,  determine whether you have viewed an item or link, or to improve our Services;
  *  **Functional Cookies.** We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies that allow us to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing or using our Services. This may include identifying you when you sign into our Website or keeping track of your specified preferences, interests, or past items viewed so that we may enhance the presentation of content on our Website;
  *  **Advertising or Targeting Cookies.** We may use first-party or third-party cookies and web beacons to deliver content, including ads relevant to your interests, on our Website or on third party sites. This includes using technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements and content that has been delivered to you, such as whether you have clicked on an advertisement.

If you would like to opt out of the Technologies we employ on our Services, you may do so by blocking, deleting, or disabling them as your browser or device permits.

#### 4\. Third-Party Websites and Social Media Platforms

The Website may contain links to other websites and other websites may reference or link to our Website or other Services. These other domains and websites are not controlled by us, and Greatist does not endorse or make any representations about Third-Party websites or social media platforms. We encourage our users to read the privacy policies of each and every website and application with which they interact. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other websites or applications. Visiting these other websites or applications is at your own risk.

The Website and our other Services may also contain links and interactive features with various social media platforms (e.g., widgets). If you already use these platforms, their cookies may be set on your device when using our Website or other Services. You should be aware that Personal Information which you voluntarily include and transmit online in a publicly accessible blog, chat room, social media platform or otherwise online, or that you share in an open forum may be viewed and used by others without any restrictions. We are unable to control such uses of your information when interacting with a social media platform, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties for any number of purposes.

#### 3\. With whom do we share that information?

We may share your information as described in this Privacy Policy (e.g., with our Third-Party service providers; to comply with legal obligations; to protect and defend our rights and property) or with your permission.

  *  **With the Healthline family of websites** : Information collected on this Website will be shared with all of Healthline Media, Inc.’s websites ([www.healthline.com](http://www.healthline.com/), [www.medicalnewstoday.com](http://www.medicalnewstoday.com/), [www.medilexicon.com](http://www.medilexicon.com/), [www.everydayfamily.com](http://www.everydayfamily.com/), and [www.greatist.com](http://www.greatist.com/)) and Apps (MS Buddy and Breast Cancer Healthline) for purposes and uses consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  *  **We Use Vendors and Service Providers.** We may share any information we receive with vendors and service providers. The types of service providers to whom we entrust Personal Information include service providers for: (i) provision of IT and related services; (ii) provision of information and services you have requested; (iii) customer service activities; (iv) payment processing; and (iv) in connection with the provision of the Website. Greatist has executed appropriate contracts with the service providers that prohibit them from using or sharing Personal Information except as necessary to perform the contracted services on our behalf or to comply with applicable legal requirements.
  *  **Business Partners.** Greatist may share Personal Information with our business partners, and affiliates for our and our affiliates’ internal business purposes or to provide you with a product or service that you have requested. Greatist may also provide Personal Information to business partners with whom we may jointly offer products or services, or whose products or services we believe may be of interest to you. In such cases, our business partner’s name will appear, along with Greatist. Greatist requires our affiliates and business partners to agree in writing to maintain the confidentiality and security of Personal Information they maintain on our behalf and not to use it for any purpose other than the purpose for which Greatist provided them.
  *  **Displaying to Other Users.** The content you post to the Website may be displayed on the Website. Other users of the Website may be able to see some information about you, such as your name if you submit a review. We are not responsible for privacy practices of the other users who will view and use the posted information.
  *  **Marketing – Interest-Based Advertising and Third Party Marketing.** Through our Services, Greatist may allow Third-Party advertising partners to set tracking tools (e.g., cookies) to collect information regarding your activities (e.g., your IP address, page(s) visited, time of day). We may also share such de-identified information as well as selected Personal Information (such as demographic information and past purchase history) we have collected with Third-Party advertising partners. These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other websites) for purposes of delivering targeted advertisements to you when you visit non-Greatist related websites within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as “interest-based advertising” or “online behavioral advertising. We may allow access to other data collected by the Website to facilitate transmittal of information that may be useful, relevant, valuable or otherwise of interest to you. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. These third parties currently may include: Acxiom, Adbridg, Akamai, Amazon, Appnexus, Criteo, District M, Facebook, Google, Index Exchange, LunaMetrics, Moat, Nexage, Oath, Oracle, OpenX, PageFair, PX, [Rubicon](https://rubiconproject.com/rubicon-project-yield-optimization-privacy-policy/), Sailthru, SendBird DBA, Teads, The TradeDesk, TripleLift, Yieldbot. If you prefer that we do not share your Personal Information with Third-Party advertising partners, you may opt out of such sharing at no cost by following the instructions in Section 6 below.
  *  **Disclosures to Protect Us or Others (e.g., as Required by Law and Similar Disclosures).** We may access, preserve, and disclose your Personal Information, other Account information, and content if we believe doing so is required or appropriate to: (i) comply with law enforcement or national security requests and legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; (ii) respond to your requests; (iii) protect yours’, ours’ or others’ rights, property, or safety; (iv) to enforce Greatist policies or contracts; (v) to collect amounts owed to Greatist; (vi) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation or prosecution of suspected or actual illegal activity; or (vii) if we, in good faith, believe that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable. In addition, from time to time, server logs may be reviewed for security purposes – e.g., to detect unauthorized activity on the Services. In such cases, server log data containing IP addresses may be shared with law enforcement bodies in order that they may identify users in connection with their investigation of the unauthorized activities.
  *  **Merger, Sale, or Other Asset Transfers.** If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, then your information may be sold or transferred as part of such a transaction as permitted by law and/or contract. In such event, Greatist will endeavor to direct the transferee to use Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such Personal Information was collected.

### 4\. Do we collect information from children?

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from our Website about children under the age of 13. We request that persons under the age of 13 not use our Website without supervision from a responsible adult. We will never request Personal Information from a child under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If We become aware that a child under the age of 13 has sent Personal Information to us without prior parental consent, We will remove his or her Personal Information from our files.

### 5\. What security measures do we take with respect to your information?

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received, and take various precautions to protect information from loss and misuse. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com).

### 6\. Opt-out rights (rights to object to processing)

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use and sharing of your Personal Information and we’ll respect the choices you make. Where you have consented to Greatist’s Processing of your Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information, you may withdraw that consent at any time and opt out of further Processing by contacting [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com). Please note that if you decide not to provide us with the Personal Information that we request, you may not be able to access all of the features of the Services. Even if you opt out, we may still collect and use non-Personal Information regarding your activities on our Website and/or information from the advertisements on Third-Party websites for non-interest based advertising purposes, such as to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

  *  **Opt-Out of our Mailings.** We may periodically send you Newsletters or other emails. When you receive such Newsletters or other emails from us, you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive. We do need to send you certain communications regarding the Services and you will not be able to opt out of those communications – e.g., communications regarding updates to our Terms or this Privacy Policy.
  *  **“Do not Track”.** Our Website does not have the capability to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from various web browsers.
  *  **Cookies and Ad Tracking.** As noted above, you may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or remove them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. Please note that cookie-based opt-outs are not effective on mobile applications. However, on many mobile devices, application users may opt out of certain mobile ads via their device settings. We also partner with third parties and partners to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. Please visit <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/> if you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising or please visit [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) if you are located in the European Union. Please note you may continue to receive generic ads, not based on your Personal Information. You can also choose not to be included in Google Analytics [here](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-analytics-opt-out/fllaojicojecljbmefodhfapmkghcbnh?hl=en).

To be clear, whether you are using our opt-out or an online industry opt-out, these cookie-based opt-outs must be performed on each device and browser that you wish to have opted-out. For example, if you have opted-out on your computer browser, that opt-out will not be effective on your mobile device. You must separately opt out on each device. Advertisements on Third-Party websites that contain the AdChoices link and that link to this Privacy Policy may have been directed to you based on anonymous, non-Personal Information collected by advertising partners over time and across websites. These advertisements provide a mechanism to opt out of the advertising partners’ use of this information for interest-based advertising purposes

### 7\. Website Location, US Transfer & Processing

THE SITE IS OPERATED BY HEALTHLINE MEDIA, INC., IN THE UNITED STATES, AND PERSONAL INFORMATION WILL BE PRIMARILY STORED IN THE UNITED STATES. BY PROVIDING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT WE COLLECT, MAINTAIN, PROCESS AND TRANSFER SUCH INFORMATION IN AND TO THE UNITED STATES AND OTHER COUNTRIES AND TERRITORIES, PURSUANT TO THE LAWS OF THE UNITED STATES OR SUCH OTHER JURISDICTIONS, WHICH MAY PROVIDE LESSER PRIVACY PROTECTIONS THAN EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA COUNTRIES, AND TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOUR INFORMATION MAY THUS BE SUBJECT TO U.S. FEDERAL AND CALIFORNIA STATE LAW AND OTHER FOREIGN LAWS AND ACCESSIBLE TO U.S. AND FOREIGN GOVERNMENTS, COURTS, LAW ENFORCEMENT AND REGULATORY AGENCIES. BECAUSE HEALTHLINE IS LOCATED IN THE UNITED STATES, THESE DATA TRANSFERS TO THE UNITED STATES ARE NECESSARY TO PROVIDE THE SERVICES TO YOU AS SET FORTH IN OUR TERMS OF SERVICE AND TO OPERATE OUR WEBSITE. WHEN APPLICABLE, WE WILL OBTAIN YOUR CONSENT FOR THESE DATA TRANSFERS TO THE UNITED STATES.

### 8\. Rights of Access, Rectification, Erasure, and Restriction

You may inquire as to whether Greatist is Processing Personal Information about you, request access to Personal Information, and ask that we correct, amend or delete your Personal Information where it is inaccurate, by contacting us at [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com). Such requests will be processed in line with local laws.

Although Greatist makes good faith efforts to provide Individuals with access to their Personal Information, there may be circumstances in which Greatist is unable to provide access, including but not limited to: where the information contains legal privilege, would compromise others’ privacy or other legitimate rights, where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the Individual’s privacy in the case in question or where it is commercially proprietary. If Greatist determines that access should be restricted in any particular instance, we will provide you with an explanation of why that determination has been made and a contact point for any further inquiries. To protect your privacy, Greatist will take commercially reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to or making any changes to your Personal Information.

### 9\. Data Retention

Greatist retains the Personal Information we receive as described in this Privacy Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, provide our Services, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements, and comply with applicable laws.

### 10\. Your California Privacy Rights

California residents may request and obtain from Us, once a year, free of charge, a list of third parties, if any, to which we disclosed their Personal Information for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year and the categories of Personal Information shared with those third parties. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain that information, please submit your request by contacting us at [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com) and indicating “California Privacy Rights” in the subject line or by writing to Us at Privacy Office, Greatist c/o Healthine, 660 Third Street, 2nd Floor, San Francisco, CA 94107.

California law requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California residents asking about the disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes. Alternatively, such businesses may adopt a policy of not disclosing Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes if a California resident opts-out.

Healthline provides you with a cost-free means to opt-out of such sharing, if you do not want Healthline to disclose information to other companies for their marketing purposes, please follow the opt-out procedures set forth above.

 **CA Eraser law**  
Under California's Digital Online Eraser Law (California Senate Bill 568), users, under the age of 18, have the right to remove, or request the removal of, content or information they have posted publicly on the Services. Please be advised that any information you post to a bulletin board, message board, chat room, community, or other forum is publicly viewable. We strongly recommend that all users avoid posting personal or sensitive information at any time. To request removal of content or information under this section, please contact us at [admin@greatist.com](mailto:admin@greatist.com), and specifically identify the content or information you would like removed.  

Please be aware that even though We will comply with your request for removal of this content or information from public view, We cannot guarantee complete or comprehensive removal. However, We may retain copies of the content or information you have previously posted on our server, and We are not required to remove your posted content or information if it has been rendered anonymously or if We are required by law to retain it. Additionally, We do not have control over third parties (i.e., other users) who may have copied or reposted the information.

### 11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If We make any material changes, then We will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### 12\. Contact Us

Greatist c/o Healthline Media, Inc.  
660 Third Street, 2nd Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94107  
Telephone Number: (+1) 415-281-3100  
E-mail address: admin@greatist.com
